Let the past die.
Star Wars: The Last Jedi is a adventure, action, science
fiction film directed by Rian Johnson.
Rey develops her newly discovered abilities with the guidance of Luke
Skywalker, who is unsettled by the strength of her powers.
Meanwhile, the Resistance prepares to do battle with the First Order.
Luke Skywalker / Dobbu Scay (voice), played by Mark Hamill.
Leia Organa, played by Carrie Fisher.
Kylo Ren, played by Adam Driver.
Rey, played by Daisy Ridley.
Finn, played by John Boyega.
Poe Dameron, played by Oscar Isaac.
Star Wars: The Last Jedi (also known as Star Wars: Episode VIII – The Last Jedi or simply The Last
Jedi) is a 2017 American epic space opera film written and directed by Rian Johnson.
Produced by Lucasfilm and distributed by Walt Disney Studios Motion Pictures, it is the second installment of the Star Wars
sequel trilogy, following The Force Awakens (2015), and the eighth episode of the nine-part "Skywalker saga".
The film's cast includes Mark Hamill, Carrie Fisher, Adam Driver, Daisy Ridley, John Boyega, Oscar Isaac, Andy Serkis, Lupita
Nyong'o, Domhnall Gleeson, Anthony Daniels, Gwendoline Christie, Kelly Marie Tran, Laura Dern, and Benicio del Toro.
The Last Jedi follows Rey as she seeks the aid of Luke Skywalker in hopes of turning the tide for the Resistance in the fight against Kylo Ren and the
First Order while General Leia Organa, Finn, and Poe Dameron attempt to escape a First Order attack on the dwindling Resistance fleet.
The film features the first posthumous film performance by Fisher, who died
in December 2016, and the film is dedicated to her memory.
The Last Jedi is part of a new trilogy of films announced after
Disney's acquisition of Lucasfilm in October 2012.
It was produced by Lucasfilm president Kathleen Kennedy and Ram Bergman
and executive produced by The Force Awakens director J.
John Williams, composer for the previous episodic
films, returned to compose the score.
A number of scenes were filmed at Skellig Michael in Ireland during pre-production in September 2015, but
principal photography began at Pinewood Studios in England in February 2016 and wrapped that July.
The Last Jedi premiered in Los Angeles on December 9, 2017, and
was released in the United States on December 15.
It grossed $1.334 billion worldwide, becoming the highest-grossing film of 2017 and the
ninth-highest-grossing film of all time by the time its theatrical run was over.
It is also the second-highest-grossing Star Wars film
and turned a net profit of $417 million.
The film was critically acclaimed  and received four nominations at the 90th Academy Awards, including Best Original
Score and Best Visual Effects, as well as two nominations at the 71st British Academy Film Awards.
A sequel, The Rise of Skywalker, concluded the sequel trilogy in 2019.
The film explores themes of bunker, space battle, defeat, failure, sequel.
The tone is thought_provoking.